# Piyush Kalyani

## Full Stack Developer

+91 78499552221
Piyush.kalyani7@gmail.com
Linked In
Digital Portfolio
GitHub

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Dataphi, Bangalore- Full Stack Developer

(JAN, 2023 - OCT, 2023)

Rajasthan, India

- Led the complete frontend development for a project, taking full responsibility for all frontend functionalities.
- Worked on 4 other projects, Transformed Figma designs into web pages using React and utilized essential libraries like Formik and Yup for validation, Zustand for state management, GraphQl, and Apollo for crud
- Worked with Django and Node for backend development, enhancing features and resolving software bugs
- Collaborated on functionality research, like creating service for aws S3 bucket integration in django using boto3, a Firebase, Django and React notification system,
- Contributed to writing efficient, maintainable code, participated in code reviews, and adapted quickly to new technologies to develop scalable web applications.

EQ Capital, Delhi- Full Stack Developer

(AUG, 2022 - DEC, 2022)

- Developed React web pages based on Figma designs and implemented JWT authentication on both frontend and backend systems.
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs in Django, integrating them with React for optimal functionality

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **ProShop E-commerce Platform**

Built an ecommerce platform using Django, React with, JWT authentication, Redux, and admin capabilities

#### Al Posture Detection for Yoga

Developed a yoga posture detection application using a variety of technologies include using Python, OpenCV, Scikit-learn, Mediapipe, Streamlit, Pandas, SQLite, and WebRTC. APublished a research paper based on this project has been approved for publication..

#### **Portfolio**

This is a personal portfolio website built using React.js, Node.js, Express.js, CSS3, VsCode, and Vercel

#### Other projects

Flutter crud notes app, Data analytics assignment, python script to change folder names, working youtube apis in django, crud form in django, crud form in mern

#### **SKILLS**

Languages Python, Sql, Javascript, C++

Technologies React, Django, Git, Docker, Node.js , Express.js, GraphQl

#### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a curious individual with a knack for problem-solving. Having spent a year as a full-stack developer, I am now focused on pursuing a career in back-end development and AI. In addition to my technical skills, I have honed my leadership and teamwork abilities through managing business operations alongside my father. With technical expertise and leadership skills, I've also extensively studied psychology. This substantial understanding of human behavior enhances my ability to work effectively in diverse teams.

### **EDUCATION**

NIIT University - M.sc Computer Science

(2019-2023)